<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<search>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>PTE Academic Reading 1</title>
    <link href="/2024/02/15/PTE-Academic-Reading-1/"/>
    <url>/2024/02/15/PTE-Academic-Reading-1/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><strong>PTE Academic Reading 1</strong></p><blockquote><p>TASK FROM <a href="https://www.examenglish.com/PTE/pte_academic_reading_1.htm">WEBSITE</a></p></blockquote><h3 id="PASSAGE"><a href="#PASSAGE" class="headerlink" title="PASSAGE"></a>PASSAGE</h3><p><em><strong>Below is a text with blanks. Select the appropriate answer choice for each blank.</strong></em></p><p>If after years of Spanish classes, some people still find it impossible to understand some native speakers, they should not worry. This does not <strong><u> ( 1 )</u></strong> mean the lessons were wasted. Millions of Spanish speakers use neither standard Latin American Spanish nor Castilian, which predominate in US schools.</p><p>The confusion is partly political - the Spanish-speaking world is very diverse. Spanish is the language of 19 separate countries and Puerto Rico. This means that there is no one standard dialect.</p><p>The most common Spanish dialect taught in the US is standard Latin American. It is sometimes called “Highland” Spanish since it is generally spoken in the <strong><u> ( 2 )</u></strong>  areas of Latin America. While each country retains its own  <strong><u> ( 3 )</u></strong> and has some unique vocabulary, residents of countries such as Mexico, Colombia, Peru, and Bolivia generally speak Latin American Spanish, especially in urban centers. This dialect is noted for its  <strong><u> ( 4 )</u></strong> of each letter and its strong “r” sounds. This Spanish was spoken in Spain in the sixteenth and seventeenth centuries, and was brought to the Americas by the early colonists.</p><p>However, the Spanish of Madrid and of northern Spain, called Castilian, developed  <strong><u> ( 5 )</u></strong> that never reached the New World. These include the pronunciation of “ci” and “ce” as “th.” In Madrid, “gracias” (thank you) becomes “gratheas” (as opposed to “gras-see-as” in Latin America). Another difference is the use of the word “vosotros” (you all, or you guys) as the informal form of “ustedes” in Spain.</p><p>Castilian sounds to Latin Americans much like British English sounds to US residents.</p><h3 id="ANSWER-TO-CHOOSE"><a href="#ANSWER-TO-CHOOSE" class="headerlink" title="ANSWER TO CHOOSE"></a>ANSWER TO CHOOSE</h3><table><thead><tr><th align="center">1</th><th align="center">2</th><th align="center">3</th><th align="center">4</th><th align="center">5</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="center">necessarily</td><td align="center">rocky</td><td align="center">thoughts</td><td align="center">pronunciation</td><td align="center">problems</td></tr><tr><td align="center">usually</td><td align="center">hidden</td><td align="center">accents</td><td align="center">collection</td><td align="center">characteristics</td></tr><tr><td align="center">only</td><td align="center">mountainous</td><td align="center">infections</td><td align="center">remembering</td><td align="center">normalities</td></tr><tr><td align="center">particularly</td><td align="center">coastal</td><td align="center">authority</td><td align="center">elucidation</td><td align="center">distinguishes</td></tr></tbody></table><p><strong>PLEASE WRITE YOUR ANSWER ON YOUR DRAFT</strong></p><div class='spoiler collapsed'>    <div class='spoiler-title'>        ANSWERS AND ANALYSIS    </div>    <div class='spoiler-content'>        <h3 id="CHECK-YOUR-ANSWERS"><a href="#CHECK-YOUR-ANSWERS" class="headerlink" title="CHECK YOUR ANSWERS"></a>CHECK YOUR ANSWERS</h3><ol><li>necessarily</li><li>mountainous</li><li>accents</li><li>pronunication</li><li>characteristics</li></ol><h3 id="ANALYSIS-OF-THE-PASSAGE"><a href="#ANALYSIS-OF-THE-PASSAGE" class="headerlink" title="ANALYSIS OF THE PASSAGE"></a>ANALYSIS OF THE PASSAGE</h3><p>The passage explains why some people who learned Spanish in the US may have difficulty understanding some native speakers. It says that Spanish is a very diverse language, with different dialects in different regions and countries. It contrasts the standard Latin American Spanish, which is taught in most US schools, with the Castilian Spanish, which is spoken in parts of Spain. It highlights some of the main differences between these two dialects, such as the pronunciation of certain letters and the use of pronouns. It also mentions the historical origins of these dialects and how they relate to each other.</p><ol><li>This does not  <strong>( 1 )</strong> mean the lessons were wasted.<br>First, let’s go through the chooses, which are all adverbs.</li></ol><ul><li><p><em><strong>necessarily</strong></em>, of course, is adverb from <em><strong>necessary</strong></em>, which means a necessary result.<br>synonyms: <em><strong>inevitably</strong></em></p></li><li><p><em><strong>usually</strong></em> is a adverb to express the frequency, which can be understood as <em><strong>under normal conditions</strong></em> or <em><strong>generally</strong></em>.</p></li><li><p><em><strong>particularly</strong></em> means more than normal, whose synonym is “<em><strong>especially</strong></em>“.</p><p>  In this sentence, the author wants to express that the lessons those people have learned were not wasted. Here is a double negative. <em><strong>Double negatives</strong></em> cancel one another and produce an affirmative, especially in Modern English, Chinese, Japanese, etc.</p></li></ul><ol start="2"><li><p>It is sometimes called “Highland” Spanish since it is generally spoken in the <strong>( 2 )</strong> areas of Latin America.<br>This is a synonymous substitution question. “<em><strong>Highland</strong></em>“ literally means a high land. “<em><strong>Mountainous</strong></em>“ means a place having many mountains. </p></li><li><p>While each country retains its own <strong>( 3 )</strong> and has some unique vocabulary, residents of countries such as Mexico, Colombia, Peru, and Bolivia generally speak Latin American Spanish, especially in urban centers. This dialect is noted for its <strong>( 4 )</strong> of each letter and its strong “r” sounds.</p></li></ol><ul><li>Let’s look at questions 3 and 4 together. It says that each country has its unique vocabulary, and later it mentions that some languages are characterized by their respective letters and the pronunciation of the “r”. Obviously, the only choice here is the word “<em><strong>accents</strong></em>.” “<em><strong>Infection</strong></em>“ means the state produced by the establishment of one or more pathogenic agents (such as a bacteria, protozoans, or viruses) in or on the body of a suitable host. </li><li>And from the following sentence, “its strong ‘r’ sounds”, we know that it is talking about <em><strong>pronunciation</strong></em>. <em><strong>Elucidation</strong></em> means an <em><strong>explanation</strong></em> that makes something clear, whose synonym is “<em><strong>clarification</strong></em>“.</li></ul><ol start="4"><li>However, the Spanish of Madrid and of northern Spain, called Castilian, developed <strong>( 5 )</strong> that never reached the New World. These include the pronunciation of “ci” and “ce” as “th.”<br>“<em><strong>Characteristics</strong></em>“ means a special quality or trait that makes a person, thing, or group different from others. In this sentence, the word “characteristics” refers to linguistic differences between Castilian Spanish and the Spanish spoken in Latin America.<br>The differences between “<em><strong>characteristic</strong></em>“ and “<em><strong>distinguish</strong></em>“ can be checked out in the <a href="###Tips">tips</a>.</li></ol>    </div></div><h3 id="Tips"><a href="#Tips" class="headerlink" title="Tips"></a>Tips</h3> <br /><div class='spoiler collapsed'>    <div class='spoiler-title'>        Tips    </div>    <div class='spoiler-content'>        <blockquote><p>This tip is from the <a href="https://thecontentauthority.com/blog/distinguishing-vs-characteristic">website</a></p></blockquote><p>The differences between “<em><strong>characteristic</strong></em>“ and “<em><strong>distinguish</strong></em>“<br>To start, both words can be used to describe unique qualities or features of something. However, “distinguishing” refers to qualities that set something apart from others, while “characteristic” refers to qualities that are typical or common to something.</p><p>For example, if you were describing a new car model, you might say that its distinguishing features are its sleek design and advanced technology. These are qualities that make the car stand out from other models on the market. On the other hand, you might say that the car’s characteristic features are its fuel efficiency and spacious interior. These are qualities that are common to many cars in the same class.</p><p>Understanding the difference between these two terms can help you more effectively communicate your thoughts and ideas. Throughout the rest of this article, we’ll explore the nuances of distinguishing vs characteristic in more detail, and provide examples of how to use each term correctly.</p><h4 id="Define-Distinguishing"><a href="#Define-Distinguishing" class="headerlink" title="Define Distinguishing"></a>Define Distinguishing</h4><p>Distinguishing refers to the act of differentiating or separating something from others based on unique qualities, features, or characteristics. It is the process of identifying what sets something apart from the rest and making it stand out. For instance, in the business world, companies use distinguishing factors to set themselves apart from their competitors and attract customers. These distinguishing factors could be in the form of unique product features, superior customer service, or innovative marketing strategies.</p><p>Furthermore, distinguishing can also refer to the ability to recognize or identify something or someone based on specific traits or characteristics. In this context, distinguishing is an important skill that is useful in various fields, such as law enforcement, medicine, and science. For example, a forensic scientist may use distinguishing features such as fingerprints, DNA, or dental records to identify a suspect or victim.</p><h4 id="Define-Characteristic"><a href="#Define-Characteristic" class="headerlink" title="Define Characteristic"></a>Define Characteristic</h4><p>A characteristic is a distinguishing feature or quality that is typical or inherent in something or someone. It is a defining trait that helps to identify or describe something. Characteristics can be physical, behavioral, or psychological in nature and can be used to differentiate between similar things or individuals. For example, the characteristic features of a lion include a mane, sharp teeth, and a powerful roar.</p><p>In addition, characteristics can also refer to the qualities or attributes that are associated with a particular group or category. These characteristics could be cultural, social, or economic in nature. For instance, the characteristics of a successful entrepreneur may include traits such as risk-taking, innovation, and perseverance.</p><h4 id="Comparison-between-Distinguishing-and-Characteristic"><a href="#Comparison-between-Distinguishing-and-Characteristic" class="headerlink" title="Comparison between Distinguishing and Characteristic"></a>Comparison between Distinguishing and Characteristic</h4><table><thead><tr><th align="center">Distinguishing</th><th align="center">Characteristic</th></tr></thead><tbody><tr><td align="center">Process of identifying what sets something apart from the rest</td><td align="center">A defining trait that helps to identify or describe something</td></tr><tr><td align="center">Used to differentiate between similar things or individuals</td><td align="center">Can be used to differentiate between groups or categories</td></tr><tr><td align="center">Can refer to the ability to recognize or identify something or someone based on specific traits or characteristics</td><td align="center">Can refer to the qualities or attributes that are associated with a particular group or category</td></tr></tbody></table>    </div></div><link rel="stylesheet" href="/css/spoiler.css" type="text/css"><script src="/js/spoiler.js" type="text/javascript" async></script>]]></content>
    
    
    
    <tags>
      
      <tag>Englsh Learning</tag>
      
    </tags>
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>first blog about my winter week</title>
    <link href="/2024/02/12/first-blog/"/>
    <url>/2024/02/12/first-blog/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<center>    <div id="cplayer-85802307"></div>    <script>      (function(){        function loadcplayer() {          if (typeof window.cplayerList === 'undefined') window.cplayerList = {};          if (typeof window.cplayerList["cplayer-85802307"] !== 'undefined') return;          if (!cplayer.prototype.add163) cplayer.prototype.add163 = function add163(id) {            if (!id) throw new Error("Unable Property.");            return fetch("https://music.huaji8.top/?id=" + id).then(function(res){return res.json()}).then(function(data){              let obj = {                name: data.info.songs[0].name,                artist: data.info.songs[0].ar.map(function(ar){ return ar.name }).join(','),                poster: data.pic.url,                lyric: data.lyric.lyric,                sublyric: data.lyric.tlyric,                src: data.url.url              }              this.add(obj);              return obj;            }.bind(this))          }          window.cplayerList["cplayer-85802307"] = new cplayer({            element: document.getElementById("cplayer-85802307"),            playlist: [{"name":"September","artist":"Earth, Wind & Fire","poster":"/img/Robot Dreams.jpg","src":"/music/September.mp3"}],            generateBeforeElement: true,            deleteElementAfterGenerate: true,            autoplay: true          });          window.cplayerList["cplayer-85802307"].add163(88701265)        }                if (typeof window.cplayer === 'undefined' && !document.getElementById("cplayer-script")) {          var js = document.createElement("script");          js.src = 'https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/gh/MoePlayer/cPlayer/dist/cplayer.js';          js.id = "cplayer-script";          js.addEventListener("load", loadcplayer);          document.body.appendChild(js);        } else {          window.addEventListener("load", loadcplayer);        }      })()    </script></center> <br /><p>Staying at home for almost 40 days, I haven’t started my essay writing. It’s about how to increase the influence of the new media(WeChat, Weibo, TikTok, etc.) of the place of interest in Qingdao. I have reviewed some essays on this subject, and many came out about 4 or 5 years ago, so this subject is not a new thing at this moment. But it’s my supervisor’s project, I have to finish it in about 15 days(haha) and publish it within the next semester. So this is an academic matter.</p><p>I don’t have many friends, I suppose. More people are having better lives than me. When going through X(Twitter, the bluebird), I see many people posting their lives and many comments below. I want that, maybe. I want people to focus on me (a little, when I post something, they hit like or comment). I tried to make peer friends on X, but they seemed not interested in me and did not want to talk to me. Maybe I am the one that no one would like to make friends with me willingly.<br><img src="https://s2.loli.net/2024/02/15/jHzPTJF3sDtodCv.jpg" alt="Robot Dreams Post"></p><p>I don’t know why I can’t read the whole book. Maybe my mind is quite impetuous or something else. But I can watch the whole movie or TV series. In the past week (maybe two weeks), I have watched <em>Ted</em> (series), <em>Robot Dreams</em> (which is so touchable that I cry for a couple of minutes after the movies), the Japanese movie <em>Monster</em> (directed by Hirokazu Kore-eda, I like the two boys in the film, which are quite cute), <em>Anatomie d’une Chute</em> (a french movie talking about family or marriage issues), <em>Marriage Story</em> (after watching <em>Anatomie d’une Chute</em>, I see this and learn more about marriage life), and <em>Sex Education Season 4</em> (haha I saw a big dick of the main character). The movie I recommend maybe is <em>Robot Dreams</em>, because it’s quite touching, no other words!</p><link rel="stylesheet" href="/css/spoiler.css" type="text/css"><script src="/js/spoiler.js" type="text/javascript" async></script>]]></content>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  <entry>
    <title>Hello World</title>
    <link href="/2024/02/12/hello-world/"/>
    <url>/2024/02/12/hello-world/</url>
    
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Welcome to <a href="https://hexo.io/">Hexo</a>! This is your very first post. Check <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/">documentation</a> for more info. If you get any problems when using Hexo, you can find the answer in <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/troubleshooting.html">troubleshooting</a> or you can ask me on <a href="https://github.com/hexojs/hexo/issues">GitHub</a>.</p><h2 id="Quick-Start"><a href="#Quick-Start" class="headerlink" title="Quick Start"></a>Quick Start</h2><h3 id="Create-a-new-post"><a href="#Create-a-new-post" class="headerlink" title="Create a new post"></a>Create a new post</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">$ hexo new <span class="hljs-string">&quot;My New Post&quot;</span><br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/writing.html">Writing</a></p><h3 id="Run-server"><a href="#Run-server" class="headerlink" title="Run server"></a>Run server</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">$ hexo server<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/server.html">Server</a></p><h3 id="Generate-static-files"><a href="#Generate-static-files" class="headerlink" title="Generate static files"></a>Generate static files</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">$ hexo generate<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/generating.html">Generating</a></p><h3 id="Deploy-to-remote-sites"><a href="#Deploy-to-remote-sites" class="headerlink" title="Deploy to remote sites"></a>Deploy to remote sites</h3><figure class="highlight bash"><table><tr><td class="gutter"><pre><span class="line">1</span><br></pre></td><td class="code"><pre><code class="hljs bash">$ hexo deploy<br></code></pre></td></tr></table></figure><p>More info: <a href="https://hexo.io/docs/one-command-deployment.html">Deployment</a></p>]]></content>
    
    
    
  </entry>
  
  
  
  
</search>
